Maurício H. Vancine

mauricio.vancine@gmail.com • GitHub • LinkedIn

SUMMARY

I am an Ecologist with a PhD in Ecology from UNESP, Brazil. My expertise includes spatial ecology, ecological modeling, and species distribution modeling (SDM). I have published over 30 papers on biodiversity and climate change in South America. I also develop tools for landscape metrics in R and GRASS GIS, and have extensive experience teaching R.

EDUCATION

Professional Experience	09/2011 - 03/2015	
	09/2011 - 03/2015	
São Paulo State University (UNESP)	Rio Claro, SP, Brazil	
BS, Ecology	09/2011 - 03/2015	
São Paulo State University (UNESP)	Rio Claro, SP, Brazil	
MS, Zoology	03/2016 - 07/2018	
São Paulo State University (UNESP)	Rio Claro, SP, Brazil	
PhD, Ecology	03/2020 - 07/2024	

State University of Campinas (Unicamp)

Postdoctoral in Spatial Ecology, LDDiv

Campinas, SP, Brazil 10/2024 - Present

TECHNICAL SKILLS

R		
tidyverse		
GRASS GIS		
QGIS		
git		
shell/bash		
Python		
LaTeX		
Google Earth Engine		
2		



- ORCID
- ResearcherID: F-7305-2016
- Scopus
- ResearchGate
- Google Scholar

LANGUAGES

- English (intermediate)
- Spanish (basic)
- Portuguese (native speaker)

REFERENCES

- Prof. Dr. Milton Cezar Ribeiro, milton.c.ribeiro@unesp.br, +55-19-3526-9680
- Prof. Dr. Célio F. B. Haddad, haddad1000@gmail.com, +55-19-3526-4302
- Prof. Dr. Mathias Pires Mistretta, mathiasmpires@gmail.com, +55-19-3521-6275

